https://www.smallbusinessbonfire.com/privacy/

Privacy PolicyEffective date: May 23, 2020The Small Business Bonfire Company (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the https://www.smallbusinessbonfire.com and https://smallbizbonfire.com websites (the “Service”).This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.Plain English SummaryWe take your privacy very seriously.Children under 18 are not eligible to use our Services and should not submit any personal information on our website.We do not actively track you as an individual.If you send us an email through the website, your name, email address and message will be emailed to us. This information is kept private. We will store this information within our own email system so that we are able to respond to you.If you comment on a blog post on this site, then your name, email address, IP address and message will be stored in our website database. This makes your name, website address and comment (but not your email address) viewable by the general public on the website.If you submit your name and email address in one of our e-mail subscription opt-in forms, your information will be added to our list in MailChimp so you can receive our newsletter. You can unsubscribe at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in each email.If you purchase or download a product, your payment will be processed securely through PayPal or Shopify.In every case, when you submit information on our site, it will only be used for the implied purpose and not shared with any third-parties (beyond those processing the data, such as MailChimp, PayPal, etc.).We do use some cookies when you browse this website. These are used to ensure proper functioning of this website, serving of ads, collection of general usage data, and to help us improve your experience on our site. This information does not identify you as an individual.We comply with GDPR (your rights are outlined in the related section below).Please read on for our complete Privacy Policy:DefinitionsServiceService is the https://www.smallbusinessbonfire.com and https://smallbizbonfire.com websites operated by The Small Business Bonfire CompanyPersonal DataPersonal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).Usage DataUsage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).CookiesCookies are small pieces of data stored on your device (computer or mobile device).Data ControllerData Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.Data Processors (or Service Providers)Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.Data Subject (or User)Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.Information Collection And UseWe collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.Types of Data CollectedPersonal DataWhile using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:Email addressFirst name and last namePhone numberCookies and Usage DataWe may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us directly.Usage DataWe may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our website that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.Tracking Cookies DataWe use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.Examples of Cookies we use:Session Cookies. We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.Preference Cookies. We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.Security Cookies. We use Security Cookies for security purposes.Advertising Cookies. Advertising Cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.Use of DataThe Small Business Bonfire Company uses the collected data for various purposes:To provide and maintain our ServiceTo notify you about changes to our ServiceTo allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do soTo provide customer supportTo gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our ServiceTo monitor the usage of our ServiceTo detect, prevent and address technical issuesTo provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such informationLegal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), The Small Business Bonfire Company legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.The Small Business Bonfire Company may process your Personal Data because:We need to perform a contract with youYou have given us permission to do soThe processing is in our legitimate interests and it’s not overridden by your rightsFor payment processing purposesTo comply with the lawRetention of DataThe Small Business Bonfire Company will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.The Small Business Bonfire Company will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.Transfer Of DataYour information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.The Small Business Bonfire Company will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.Disclosure Of DataLegal RequirementsThe Small Business Bonfire Company may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:To comply with a legal obligationTo protect and defend the rights or property of The Small Business Bonfire CompanyTo prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the ServiceTo protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the publicTo protect against legal liabilitySecurity Of DataThe security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. The Small Business Bonfire Company aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you. Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.The right of rectification. You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.The right to object. You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.The right of restriction. You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.The right to data portability. You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.The right to withdraw consent. You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where The Small Business Bonfire Company relied on your consent to process your personal information.Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).Service ProvidersWe may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.AnalyticsWe may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.Google AnalyticsGoogle Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/AdvertisingWe may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you to help support and maintain our Service.Google AdSense DoubleClick CookieGoogle, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Service. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other websites on the Internet.You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings web page: http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/BuySellAdsTheir Privacy Policy can be viewed at  https://www.buysellads.com/about/privacyLead Generation and Email MarketingWe may use third-party Service Providers to collect information and send email marketing messages.The Service Providers we work with are:MailChimpTheir Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/OptinMonsterTheir Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://optinmonster.com/privacy/NinjaFormsTheir Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://ninjaforms.com/privacy-policy/Ordering and PaymentsWe may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.The payment processors we work with are:PayPal Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-fullPrintfulTheir Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacyShopifyTheir Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://www.printful.com/policies/privacyLinks To Other SitesOur Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.Children’s PrivacyOur Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.Changes To This Privacy PolicyWe may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page, and updating the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.Contact UsIf you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us here: https://www.smallbusinessbonfire.com/contact-us/The Small Business Bonfire is a collaborative community for entrepreneurs that provides actionable business resources, tips and tools you can use immediately to help your small business succeed.Subscribe to the Small Business Bonfire NewsletterAnd get your free one-page marketing plan template.
Recent Posts
What You Should Know About the Employee Retention Credit Updated on Dec 10, 2020 | COVID-19, Employees, Financials
10 of the Best Ways to Improve Your Mental Health Updated on Dec 10, 2020 | COVID-19, Wellness at Work
2021 Digital Marketing Trends That Will Impact Your Small Business Updated on Dec 7, 2020 | Business Trends, Digital Marketing, Marketing, Online Business
How Small Businesses Can Successfully Recruit IT Specialists Updated on Dec 3, 2020 | Employees
6 Types of Remote Working Tools You Need for Your Small Business Team Updated on Dec 2, 2020 | COVID-19, Virtual Teams, Work from Home
How to Incorporate User-Generated Content In Your Marketing Strategy Updated on Dec 1, 2020 | Digital Marketing, Online Business
Landing Page Conversion Rates: 7 Content Tips to Help Improve Yours Updated on Nov 30, 2020 | Online Business, Website Tips
8 Business Ideas for Teens Who Are Ready to Become Entrepreneurs Updated on Nov 18, 2020 | Starting a Business
How to Stay Motivated As a Solopreneur: 6 Strategies That Work Updated on Nov 30, 2020 | Productivity, Starting a Business
Three Low-Cost Pandemic-Friendly Business Ideas to Consider Updated on Nov 18, 2020 | COVID-19, Starting a Business
Facebook 10,520 Followers
Twitter 20,952 Followers
Pinterest 4,592 Followers
Instagram 2,037 Followers
CategoriesBlogging (87)Branding (66)Business Growth (312)Business Mistakes (48)Business Planning (86)Business Tools (26)Business Trends (17)Business Writing (59)Collaboration (41)Content Marketing (69)COVID-19 (34)Customer Service (97)Data & Analytics (18)Development (86)Digital Marketing (91)Ecommerce (39)Email Marketing (33)Emerging Media (9)Employees (190)Ethics (6)Facebook (22)Featured (8)Financials (209)Free Resources (24)Giveaway (6)Goal Setting (30)Green Business (13)Holidays (28)Infographics (30)Instagram (19)Leadership (13)Legal (23)Logo Design (6)Marketing (449)Mobile (53)Motivation (51)Networking (43)Online Business (308)Operations (43)Productivity (166)Retail (9)Safety (11)Sales (61)Security (45)SEO (73)Small Business Events (11)Social Media (183)Software/Business Services (30)Sponsored (9)Starting a Business (380)Technology (206)Travel (11)Twitter (11)Video (22)Virtual Teams (15)Website Tips (78)Weekly Roundup (68)Wellness at Work (34)WordPress Tips (21)Work from Home (57)Work/Life Balance (66) This website uses cookies to improve your experience. Got it, thanks! Read MorePrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close Privacy OverviewThis website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Necessary Always EnabledNecessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessaryAny cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.Pin It on Pinterest
Share This
Twitter
Facebook
Pinterest
LinkedIn
Buffer
Gmail
Print Friendly
